<!DOCTYPE html>
<html lang="en-US">
<head>
    <link rel="stylesheet" href="../style and scripts/my_style_sheet.css">
</head>
<body>
<div id="backstop">
   
    <p></p>
    <p id="breaker"> </p>
    <p> 

        [Click. Click. Air conditioning]
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        -Thank you for meeting with me, Mayor Perulo. I have a couple of questions about my documentary that I would like to ask you. First off, what does Witches day mean to you?
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        Well, it’s all about the town, is it not? Witch day is a celebration of old Spring. The beautiful folks of our community organize a charming party to celebrate the town’s history. The witches come through to help in that revelry, and for that, we should be grateful to them. 
        I am putting forth, to be approved by the council of course, for the renaming of the celebration to Cold Spring Innovator’s day. After all, who are we really celebrating? The witches? They come into our town once a year and pay us no mind whatsoever. I love the witches as much as anybody but I just get to thinking sometimes, as any good mayor would. What have the witches ever done for us?
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        -What abou-
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        Now I know, I know: witches support the local tourism trade. Our cavern is top-notch! It supports almost a quarter of the town and the witches help keep the crowds coming in. But ever since covid, the massive hit to tourism, and many in the town getting laid off, should we not have something a little more stable to affix our sturdy and beloved community to? The witches are just transitory.
        In the grand scheme of things, what do they actually contribute? We already have Halloween, why do we need another holiday based on outdated rituals?
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        Cold Spring Innovator’s day will emphasize the prized brains of our community. Plus, it will give a great landing platform to a few innovative firms considering using beautiful Cold Spring as a headquarters. I believe, as elected officials of the people of Cold Spring, in the growth and prosperity offered by these firms. And I have more faith in them than I ever had in a pair of quarreling, dangerous witches who raid our town every 200 days. 
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        That is why, with the approval of the council, of course, I am helping sponsor an innovator's day effort to trap the witches that besiege our town. 
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        -Mr. Mayor! You are making a witch trap? That is fantastic news! What is your idea?
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        Our innovation team has done a marvelous job this year. They, in front of some stakeholders from various firms, will demonstrate the essential know-how of Cold Springers. I, of course, will be cutting the ribbon and pulling the string. 
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        -But what is the actual trap?
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        It is a simple and clever piece of innovation! You will see it, along with the rest of Cold Spring, later tonight. Now, I have an 11 am lunch I cannot be late for. 
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        [Click. Click. A low, warm buzz. Many low voices talk loudly about chili in the background.]
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        -ew questions for a recording I am doing about Witches Day?
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        Tewpence, hey. Good to see you. How’s your dad? 
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        -He is well. I do not think he wants to see you after last Saturday though. Maybe steer clear of the block for a little while. 
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        Heard. Why are you asking questions about Witches' Day?
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        -I want to hear what Cold Springers have to say about it. I want to be able to show others and, you know, I never really spoke with anyone seriously about it before today. It feels like we are all clouds arranged in a beautiful sky every Witches Day. To the onlooker, it appears that we have all been carefully arranged. We look beautiful as a composition but no one took the time to arrange us. Who came up with the Witches Day celebrations and what aspects of it are important to people?
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        Oh well… so you want like, what I feel about the whole thing?
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        [A low voice shouts, and a series of clangs ring out over the warm buzz.]
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        Oh, Chili's ready. Want some? 
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        -No thanks, Lawrence. Mom made some Catfish Po Boys earlier. 
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        Mind if I answer your questions at the table?
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        [The low voices get louder. They are still all talking about chili and the merits of it being hot or mild.]
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        -Witches Day is always busy for us. Funnily enough, Tom did some data crunching and found out that Witches Day always has one of the lowest death rates of the year. Mayor Perulo has us out in force, and there are always a few kids with twisted ankles from falling off of witch trap ladders and down wolf holes but, yeah, it’s a bit of a holiday for us because of that. 
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        [A higher voice calls from beyond the clanging and the low hum.]
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        Lawrence set up this chili contest to celebrate. You should let him eat the goods. He’s gotta judge the thing.
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        Thanks, Lainy. Look Tewpence. We’ve been having so many more overdoses in the past few years. The town’s aging population is in poor health; so many of them worked in the silver plants. It’s nice that even if it is a fluke, to think that there is a day every year that we get a break. And a break for a reason.
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        -Do you think the witches have anything to do with the low death rate?
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        Well…
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        [Clanging drowns the microphone. Then, dozens of pieces of metal on ceramic.]
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        Oh, that is good Gadot. Do I think the witches have anything to do with the death rate? Yes and no. The witches don’t do anything to us. For as loud and bright as they are, I have never seen, never even heard of any healing magic done by the witches. No injuries were caused by the twisted sisters either. I think, especially for those in bad health… Well.
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        [The clanging stops and the low hum is joined only by the sound of ceramic clacking, folding chairs shifting, and feet shuffling across concrete floor.]
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        Feeling a shift in the mood of those around you is strong. It can give life to people who have very little left. It’s fleeting but, for a day or two, the change in routines, the sudden comings and goings, the preparations, and the excitement, it can give a little life to whoever needs it most. The witches don’t do anything to heal people. But the holiday props people up a bit. It gives everyone something easy to focus on. 
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        -Thank you, Lawrence. I should be getting to my mom’s house fo-
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        [Clanging again. This time, much louder. It is battering and comes a thousand times a second. A dozen folding chairs slide out, and a few clatter to the floor. Bare feet slide into heavy boots and a dozen low voices, each separate but part of some greater will, puppet bodies into heavy suits. The engines, like avalanches, reverberate. Click. Click. The sound of engines remains but is joined by the woosh of accelerated water.]
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        It is 79 degrees and humid this Sunday night here in Cold Springs, Ohio. There has been an accident along the Witches Day route. The old mining shaft burst into flames just twenty minutes ago. Firefighters and EMTs are on the scene and working hard to make sure everyone is safe and sound. Three engines are here working this fire, it's a blaze. I see Lawrence working outside. I will not be getting in his way but it is comforting to see him so calm and professional. It looks like the firefighters are pulling people out of the building. That is … Jimmy Lamont! From my year. And Tony Block, also my year. Valentina Rammond, Bryn Strong, King Smoug. It is the innovation club. They look okay. No burns visible from where I am. I hope they’re okay. The mayor just came out of the shaft. Looks like he is okay too. Bryn! Bryn! Bryn. What happened? Are you okay?
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        Twoppe! I’m okay. I’m okay. Oh my god, I’m okay. We were testing our witch trap and bang you know? Oh my god did that thing pop. We built it in the shaft for the chimney effect. Wanted to use the mountain to breathe fire at the witches when they came through. But man, did that not work. Jesus, I’m okay. They’re all out right? Everyone okay?
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        Everyone got out without a scratch. You are all safe. 
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        Thank god! Thank god!
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        [Corce, jittery laughing slowly fades into the sound of engines and water.]
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        King! King! Are you all right? What hap-. The sky has just begun to change. It is … 78 degrees and humid this Sunday night here in Cold Spring, Ohio.
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        [Labored breathing and heavy footfalls carry the microphone away from the engines and water.]
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        The witches have just arrived. 
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        [Cheering, shouting, and the occasional firework buzzing.]
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        Mrs. Laroche! Good to see you here. Can you tell me a bit about what you see? 
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        Hello Tewpence. I brought something to throw. It’s my mom’s old necklace. How am I supposed to know when to do it? And sure. It looks like a cloud of green and purple coming from the south. I don’t really see anything yet. How fast do they come through? Those two kids should not be in the middle of the road, should they?
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        Oh, Lainy and Moira are getting their trap set up. I am excited to see it. 
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        Well beyond them, and there is no way I would let my two kids stand in the middle of the street like that, I can see flashing lights coming from the cloud.
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        [Whack! And an echo.]
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        Was that the witches? That was a hell of a crack. 
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        It was! They are still a little ways away so it will be hard to hear exactly what they are saying for a little while. Can you tell me about the necklace? 
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        That was a voice? Yeah, it was just something she wore when she performed. She did stand up after she retired. She constantly laughed during her sets. A jittery, corky laugh. She was constantly laughing at home too. Way more than I ever did. And I’ll see this again when the witches come back?
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        Every Witches Day.
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        Sounds nice. 
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        [A high-pitched wail shines through the recording. Then, two rolling lines of words, said simultaneously and pronounced cleanly, quiet the crowd. The sounds of the words are English but without meaning. Like two great actors spouting the most incomprehensible Shakespeare.]
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        Well, I’m seeing them now, the witches. They're coming through fast aren’t they, my god! Yellow and blue and purple and marble? Sorry, I mean, all of those colors are coming off of them. It looks like they’re grappling with one another, throwing each other down and up and on the ground! Oh my god, the kids! You’re sure they’ll be alright? 
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        Watch! They will be absolutely fine. I think this is their best idea yet. Oh, throw the necklace now! 
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        What are they doing? Why are they dressed as ghosts? What’s coming off of the witches? Are those shoes?
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        They are returning all of the gifts we gave them. Oh, here they go!
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        [Over the recording, two kids are singing something. As their song goes along, they become more sure of themselves and sing louder.]
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        Witchies, Witchies, comie here. 
        Gimmie, your mommy, a kiss on the ear. 
        Witchies, Witchies, quickly now.
        Or we’ll turn to a big old cow.
        Witchies, Witchies, kissies please, 
        It’s time for your old mom to go to bed!
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        They’re about to be hit!
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        [A beautiful cackle. Long and salty.]
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        The witches zoomed just around the twins and blew them simultaneous kisses. I cannot believe these two. Their traps always seem to work. 
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        [A tremendous woosh and gush comes out of the blue.]
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        What happened to the street? There’s water gushing out of the sewers! It’s filling up the streets! 
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        [Hiss.] 
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        The water flowed back to the mine! It looks like it helped to put the fire out. Wow, there is a lot of steam coming off of that thing. 
        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        [As the sound of the witches dies away, only flowing water can be heard. Soon, footsteps and a smattering of chat. Then, the cracking of aluminum cans, the popping of fireworks, and laughing. Click.]
        </p>

        <p id="breaker"> </p>
        
 
   
</div>
</body>

</html>